创世之初 冥冥之中
In the beginning, there was darkness...
随着轰的一声
and then, bang...
诞生了无限膨胀的
giving birth to an endless expanding existence...
时间 空间和物质
of time, space, and matter.
现在 所见超乎我们的想象
Now, see further than we've ever imagined...
超越了我们生存的限制
beyond the limits of our existence...
这个空间我们称之为"宇宙"
in a place we call "The Universe."
性是人类最基本的原动力之一
Sex is the most basic of human drives.
它繁衍物种 沟通我们
It propagates the species, connects us...
提供愉悦 渗透我们的文化
provides pleasure, and permeates our culture.
随着人类将自己的栖息地
As human beings expand their habitat...
扩大到广袤的太空
to include the vast reaches of space...
我们是否准备带上性事呢?
are we prepared to take sex with us?
人类本身的未来
The future of the human race itself...
可能取决于一个问题:
may eventually depend on one question:
我们在太空中会有性事吗?
can we have sex in space?
首个婴儿诞生于外部世界
The first baby to be born off-world...
将可能是人类有历史意义的日子
is going to be a historic day for humanity.
我认为人们会惊异于
I think that people will be surprised...
太空中的性事究竟是怎么回事
at how much work it is to have sex in space.
你已经听说了1英里高空俱乐部
You've heard of the mile-high club.
我一直在谈论200英里太空俱乐部
I've been talking about the 200-mile-high club.
准备体验《太空性事》
Prepare to experience "Sex in Space."
宇宙:太空性事
在科学家展望我们在太空中的前景时
When scientists envision our future in space...
他们看到了月球上的城市 火星上的殖民地
they see cities on the Moon, colonies on Mars...
最终 人类散布在整个宇宙
and, eventually, human expansion throughout the cosmos.
如果我们要从地球物种
If we are going to make the jump...
跳跃到太空物种
between a terrestrial species and a celestial species...
性和生殖将是这一跳跃的组成部分
sex and reproduction will be part of that leap.
但是 实际上
But, actually, performing sex in space...
太空玩性谈何容易
is easier said than done.
太空性事的头号敌人
The number one enemy of sex in space...
就是牛顿的运动定律
is Isaac Newton's laws of motion.
第三运动定律:
The third law of motion:
对于每一个运动 都存在着一个等量的反作用
for every action, there's an equal and opposite reaction.
假如你推某个东西 它也会反推你
lf you push against something, it pushes against you.
因而我们将不得不学习 不厌其烦地学习
So we're going to have to learn, tediously...
涉及太空性事的人类行为新规律
a new law of human behavior when it comes to sex in space.
准备测试新规律 大胆去闯
Ready to test that law and boldly go...
那里在万那.邦塔(科幻片《超级战警》作者) 之前尚无男女到过
where no man and woman have gone before is Vanna Bonta.
万那是量子科幻小说《飞行》的作者
Vanna is the author of the quantum fiction novel "Flight"...
诗人 以及专业太空律师
a poet, and a dedicated space advocate.
曾经有人对我说起
Once, someone I was working with said...
告诉你 万那 有人在考虑
"You know, Vanna, some people think about...
他们明天午餐吃什么
"what they're having for lunch tomorrow...
而你在考虑未来几百年的事情
"and you're thinking hundreds of years into the future."
如今在内华达州拉斯维加斯
Today, in Las Vegas, Nevada...
万那和她的老公艾伦.纽科姆
Vanna and her husband, Allen Newcomb...
在亲历亲为
are doing their part...
展示人类未来的太空经历
to usher in the future of human space exploration.
万那和艾伦在彩排 为了测试首套衣服
Vanna and Allen are rehearsing for a test of the first garment...
那是为帮助太空失重环境中的
created to help facilitate sexual intimacy...
性行为而制作的
in the weightlessness of space.
万那称她的发明为二人套
Vanna calls her invention the 2suit.
二人套是实用型服装
The 2suit is a utilitarian garment...
其本身的功能是飞行装
that functions by itself as a flight suit...
可以拉开和粘上尼龙扣来粘贴到情人的衣服上
and can unzip or attach with Velcro and attach to a partner's suit...
里面非常轻巧的可以延伸的织物
with very lightweight fabric inside that can expand.
万那和艾伦将进行她的二人套的首次测试
Vanna and Allen will conduct the first ever test...
登上重力一号 波音737改造的飞机
of her 2suit aboard G-Force One, a modified Boeing 737...
它会产生失重的效果
that produces the effect of weightlessness.
作为重力一号的早期舱内设计师
As the early designer of the interiors for G-Force One...
我们讨论过好多好多东西
we discussed many, many things...
可能会发生在那种环境中的各种情况
that could happen within that environment...
性事啊 亲昵啊 情侣或更多人漂浮在一起
and sex and intimacy and floating as couples or more together...
肯定是个问题
is certainly one of the things.
我认为二人套的概念是完美的
l think the concept of the 2suit is perfect...
但是我也只是认为想法背后的哲理
but I also think just the philosophy behind thinking...
超出了为两个人愉悦
thinking beyond normal into creating a suit...
而发明服装的一般思维
for two people is wonderful.
这不是万那和艾伦在重力一号的首次旅行
This isn't Vanna and Allen's first trip aboard G-Force One.
万那曾经在2004年受邀参加这飞机的处女航
Vanna was invited on the aircraft's maiden voyage in 2004.
那一刻 我首次体验到了超重和失重
The moment I first experienced gravity lift and micro-gravity...
它完全不同于我的想象
it was unlike anything I ever imagined...
你可以想到身体等东西
and you can think something physically...
以及随心所欲
and execute it by intent.
比如 我想到过空翻
For example, I barely thought "somersault"...
不费吃灰之力
and it was effortless.
令人兴奋不已
It was exhilarating.
在试图开始与老公卿卿我我时
It was while trying to initiate an intimate moment with her husband...
万那意识到那方面缺乏失重的经验:
that Vanna realized something was lacking from the weightless experience:
身体接触
physical intimacy.
我们翻跟斗 转身 漂浮 做着各种杂技
We somersaulted, we spun around, we flew, did various acrobatics...
但是却有一个感受 那就是
but one impression that l really had...
在零重力下就是没有吸引力
was just how zero, zero gravity is in that there is no attraction.
要知道 你就是不能 你确实不能
You know, you just couldn't-- You just couldn't quite--
要知道 你确实要下一番功夫才行
You know, you just really had to work at it.
就为了亲吻一下
Just for a kiss.
万那看到了未来的需求 决定现在就来填补它
Vanna saw a future need and decided to fill it now.
我提出二人套的概念
The idea came to me of a 2suit...
就是一套服装 让你可以勾搭上你的情侣
which was a suit that you can hook up with your partner...
这样你就不必刻意去搂紧或紧抓不放
and then you don't have to work at staying close or hanging out.
这不仅对于性活动
And it's not just for sexual activity...
而且亲昵 亲昵的感觉
but intimacy, the feeling of intimacy and closeness...
亲密无间的身体接触 拥抱 惬意 持续
of physical proximity, cuddling, cozy, hanging out.
成对的二人套已经生产出来了
A pair of 2suit prototypes have been manufactured...
将在内华达上空3.8万英尺处
and they're about to be thoroughly tested...
进行认真的测试
38,000 feet above Nevada.
我很激动 参加二人套的测试
I'm very excited to be testing the 2suit...
实际上创造未来是很激动的
and actually creating the future is very exciting...
现在对我来说是非常感动的
and very profoundly moving to me right now.
与二人套发明者结婚无疑是一炮升天
Being married to the creator of the 2suit is a real rocket ride.
万那是一位出色的 有创造力的文艺复兴女子
Vanna is a brilliantly creative Renaissance woman...
此外 她热情奔放
and, besides, she's hot.
为了营造零重力的效果
To create the effects of zero gravity...
重力一号采用了抛物线垂直飞行的轨迹
G-Force One takes a parabolic vertical flight path.
在抛物线顶端的飞机试验弧段
As the pilot arcs the aircraft over the peak of the parabola...
乘客体验到了30秒钟的失重
the occupants experience about 30 seconds of weightlessness.
同样的效果 你可以在过山车上感觉到
It's the same effect you feel on a roller coaster...
你越过山顶 飞出座位
when you go over the top of a hill and fly out of your seat.
飞行期间 万那和艾伦的挑战
During the flight, Vanna and Allen's challenge...
就是完成一个对接演习 接吻 然后脱离
is to complete one docking maneuver, kiss, and then undock...
要在飞机走出抛物线和重力恢复之前完成
before the aircraft comes out of its parabola and gravity returns.
万那发明了她的二人套
Vanna created her 2suit...
以供长期太空飞行穿戴
to be worn on long-duration space flights.
但是在重力一号上 她和艾伦只有
But on G-Force One, she and Allen will have...
不足30秒钟的失重状态
less than 30 seconds of weightlessness...
穿上套装进行表演
to put the suit through its paces.
在头两个抛物线上 万那和艾伦
During the first two parabolas, Vanna and Allen...
各自适应着失重
acclimate themselves to weightlessness.
到了第三个抛物线 他们的对接尝试
On the third parabola, their docking attempt is interrupted...
因为飘忽不定的乘客群而被迫中断
by a group of wayward passengers.
在接下来的几个抛物线里
During the next several parabolas...
万那和艾伦争分夺秒
Vanna and Allen struggle against time...
对抗着失重实现对接
and the whims of weightlessness to achieve docking.
最后到了第八个抛物线 实现了成功的对接 接吻
Finally, on the eighth parabola, a successful docking, a kiss...
成功的脱离
and a successful undocking.
不错 我认为任务很成功
Well, l would call the mission a success.
我认为这是个有效的设计 我想在
I think it's a functional design, and I would like to test it...
更长时间零重力条件下来进行测试
in more prolonged zero-gravity conditions...
因为我认为那确实是下一步要做的
because l think that really will be the next step.
我对此很高兴 真的喜欢上了飞行
I was pleased with it and really enjoyed the flight.
万那的二人套
Vanna's 2suit is just one small step...
只是人类殖民宇宙的小小的一步
towards humankind colonizing the universe.
巨大的飞跃将发生在
The giant leap will occur when we actually begin...
我们开始在太空中生儿育女时
making babies in space.
我们对太空中的
What little we know about reproductive...
生殖与发展生物学知之甚少
and developmental biology in space...
这就对我们提出了巨大的问题
suggests to us that there are going to be huge problems...
只要物种试图跃身一变
if the species tries to make a single jump...
从地球文明变为失重文明
from a terrestrial civilization to a weightless civilization.
首先面临的问题就是零重力
The first problem is zero gravity...
或更确切的说 是微重力
or more accurately, micro-gravity.
航天飞机或空间站围绕地球时
When we have a space shuttle or space station orbiting Earth...
我们称其为微重力 因为重力还是存在的
we call it micro-gravity because gravity is still present...
依然有轻微的拉力拉向地球
and there's still a slight pull towards the Earth.
只是不很强
It's just not very strong.
一旦你将人放到微重力环境中
When you take a human and put them in a micro-g setting...
骨骼就会流失钙
the bones are losing calcium...
心脏就会变得懒惰 会丧失质量
the heart is getting lazy, it's losing mass...
骨骼肌慢慢失去质量
the skeletal muscle is losing mass.
你会丢失红细胞 丢失血浆量
You lose red cell mass, you lose plasma volume.
第二个问题是高能辐射
The second problem is high-energy radiation...
原子级粒子充满了太空
atomic-scale particles that fill the vacuum of space.
暴露于辐射有可能造成不孕症
There is a possibility of sterility caused by exposure to radiation...
这种情况
and this has been something...
我们已经从核电站看到了
that we've seen from nuclear power plants...
人们工作在高剂量辐射环境中
and people who work around high doses of radiation.
地球上的这些辐射粒子
These radiation particles on Earth were shielded...
被地球大气层里的磁场屏蔽了
by a magnetic field in the Earth's atmosphere...
但是在太空中 它们可以畅通无阻
but in space, they can move unimpeded...
直到碰到人体组织这样的东西
until they hit something like human tissue.
一旦这种情况发生 它们会杀死细胞
And when that happens, they can kill the cell...
或对其产生危害
or they can just damage it.
一旦它们危害到细胞 结果就是
And when they damage it, what happens is...
它们会去走你DNA的一部分
they will take out part of your DNA...
但是细胞仍能存活和复制 于是细胞就会发生变异
but the cell still lives and replicates, and that cell then mutates.
这种情况类似于我们所知的地球上的癌症
This is the same thing as we know of as cancer on Earth.
为了了解微重力和高能辐射
To see how micro-gravity and high-energy radiation...
对性繁殖可能造成的影响
might affect sexual reproduction...
科学家已经在太空中进行了动物实验
scientists have conducted animal tests in space.
动物实验其实是第一步
Animal studies are really the first step...
然后我们才可以将人送入太空
before we can take a human into space...
使他们怀孕生育
and have them become pregnant or give birth.
这样你看到了受孕
So you have conception.
你看到胎盘的成长
You have the development of a placenta.
你看到了产前器官系统的成长
You have the development of organ systems prenatally.
你看到了生产过程
You have the process of birth.
所有这些东西是很正常的
All of these things are in common...
无论是小动物还是人类
between small animals and humans.
首次太空中成功交配的动物
The first animal to successfully mate in space...
是青鳉鱼 是在1994年的航天飞机上
was the medaka fish, which flew on the space shuttle in 1994.
青鳉鱼的研究 太空中交配的动物
The medaka study, the animals mated in space...
它们在太空中产卵孵化
they laid eggs, and the babies hatched in space...
告诉我们 繁殖的各个方面
telling us that all of those aspects of reproduction...
对于鱼类是有可能的
are possible in a fish.
但是人类是哺乳动物 哺乳动物繁育
But people are mammals, and there are many intricate phases...
涉及到许多复杂的阶段
involved in mammalian development...
从一开始受孕 一直到出生
from the start, conception, all the way through birth.
1995年搭载航天飞机的一项老鼠实验
A study with rats aboard a 1995 space shuttle mission...
表明新生儿有异常的表现
showed an abnormal behavior in newborns.
出生一周后
For the first week after birth, the young rat pups...
小幼鼠不会自己翻过身来
weren't able to turn themselves from their backs to their bellies...
这是老鼠十分典型的反应
which is a very characteristic response in rats.
我们认为在微重力下饲养它们
We think that rearing them in micro-gravity...
造成了其感知系统受重力的刺激不够
caused that sensory system to be understimulated by gravity...
因此 其发育在太空中是不同的
and, hence, it developed differently in space.
其他实验已经表明甚至还有更加严重的后果
Other experiments have shown even more severe effects.
研究表明 进入过太空的雄鼠
Studies have shown that male rats that have flown in space...
当你在它们经过飞行后 将其与未经飞行的雌鼠配对
when you mate them to non-flown female rats after their flight...
其后代会表现出很大程度的发育迟钝
the offspring exhibits a lot of growth retardation...
产生的后果甚至会有脑积水
and even developmental effects like hydrocephaly...
肾脏异常
kidney abnormalities.
研究人员认为更多的动物实验是必需的
Researchers agree that more animal studies are needed...
然后我们才能开始
before we can begin to study...
研究人类的太空性繁殖
human sexual reproduction in space.
我们有了近50年的人类太空飞行
We're approaching year 50 of human space flight...
我们还是必须观察一种哺乳动物完整的过程
and we still have yet to see a single mammal go all the way...
从卵到胚胎 一直到妊娠
from an egg to an embryo, all the way through gestation...
到出生 在零重力环境中发育
be born, develop in a zero-g setting...
然后有了太空繁育的第一代
and then have the first generation reproduce in space.
因此我认为我们需要新的真正了解的优先权
So I think we need a new priority to really understand...
充分了解哺乳动物
fully understand mammalian development...
在失重环境中的生长
in a weightless setting.
人来太空繁殖的关键
The key to human reproduction in space...
将取决于动物的研究
will come via animal studies.
但是动物研究也没有预测到
But no animal study could've predicted...
一个宇航员被称为伟哥效果
what one astronaut referred to as the Viagra effect.
...发现号航天飞机升空
...and liftoff of Space Shuttle Discovery.
美国航天局和俄罗斯联邦航天局都声称
Both NASA and the Russian Federal Space Agency have stated...
他们从未实验过
that they've conducted no experiments...
人类性行为或性繁殖
into human sexuality or reproduction.
但是这并不意味着 科学家不能苟合在一起
But that doesn't mean scientists can't piece together...
那是有可能发生的 只要一男一女
what might occur if a man and a woman...
尝试在太空中怀上一个孩子
made an attempt to conceive a child in space.
如果男性没有本能地激起性欲 性交就不可能发生
lf the male isn't physically aroused, then intercourse isn't possible.
不过 根据至少有一位宇航员的说法
However, according to at least one astronaut...
处在太空中会产生他所谓的伟哥效果
being in space produced what he called "the Viagra effect."
在他的《驾驭火箭》一书中
In his book "Riding Rockets"...
航天飞机任务专家迈克.穆莱恩
Space shuttle mission specialist Mike Mullane...
写到了持久 有时痛苦的状况
wrote about a persistent and at times painful condition...
那是他每天醒来时都要经历的
he experienced every day when he woke up.
航天局飞行外科医生认为血液
NASA flight surgeons believe the redistribution of blood...
在微重力下再分配是其肇因
in micro-gravity is the cause.
血液的流动可能使男人更愿意在太空中有性行为
The fluid shift may make it easier for men to have sex in space.
那可能是个有趣的事情 我们必须来进行研究
That may be an interesting thing that we'll have to investigate.
事实上 有证据表明 男人往往太空中更容易勃起
In fact, there's some evidence that men tend to have erections...
因为血液的流动
easier in space because of the fluid shift.
结论是?
The conclusion?
男性无需担心太空中的性功能
Males need to worry less about performance issues...
会差于地球上
in space than they do on Earth.
我不确定 人类在微重力中的性交
I'm not sure that human beings would have much trouble...
会有很多麻烦
with the actual act of mating itself in micro-gravity...
我指的是 在保证他们的性欲方面
I mean, providing they had the desire.
我们确实有四个航天飞机成员的小样本
We do have a small sample size of four shuttle crew members...
他们基本上都说 他们的性欲
who basically said that their sexual desire...
在轨道上确实降低了
actually decreased on orbit, and this correlated...
这也关系到睾丸激素水平的下降
with decreased testosterone levels as well.
那是个小样本
Now, that's a small sample size...
但是它确实给了你有可能发生在零重力中的迹象
but it does give you an indication of what might be going on in zero g.
下一个未知数就是微重力是否有可能影响到受精
The next unknown is how micro-gravity might affect fertilization.
长期暴露在太空辐射中
Long-term exposure to space radiation...
不但有可能危害到精子
could damage both the sperm...
而且很有可能 所有女性的卵子
and, quite possibly, all of the female's eggs.
如果她处于生育年龄
lf she's of child-bearing age...
那么其中的一个卵子遭到了危害
then one of those eggs, if it has been damaged...
就会产下有某种先天性缺陷的孩子
could produce a child that had some sort of birth defect...
或者孩子夭折胎中
or the failure of the child to be born alive.
一旦释放到输卵管里
Once released into the fallopian tubes...
数以百万计的精子游向卵子
the millions of sperm swim towards the egg.
一个紧抓不放的精子会钻入其中
One tenacious sperm will burrow inside...
开始了受精的过程
beginning the process of fertilization.
一旦卵子移出输卵管
Once the egg is moving down the fallopian tube...
被推入子宫
and is propelled to the uterus...
那么它会被嵌入子宫壁
will it embed itself in the wall of the uterus...
开始形成血供和胎盘
and begin developing a blood supply and a placenta...
发育为婴儿吗?
and grow into a baby?
我们真的不知道
We just don't know that.
如果受精成功
If fertilization is successful...
细胞分裂和胚胎发育就开始了
cell division and growth of the embryo begins.
随着胚胎发育成胎儿
As the embryo develops into a fetus...
重力变得越发关键
gravity becomes increasingly critical.
对于人类胎儿 足月妊娠约36周
For a human fetus, a full-term pregnancy is about 36 weeks.
到了26周左右 胎儿在中间悬浮着
And up to about the 26th week, the fetus is neutrally buoyant.
此后 胎儿开始密度增大
After that, the fetus becomes more dense...
因此 胎儿往往
and so the fetus tends to sink in the uterus...
下沉带子宫的羊水中
in the amniotic fluid.
因此根据这一点
So from that point forward...
看来的确在胎儿器官系统的发育过程中
there does seem to be a lot of effects of gravity...
重力有很大的影响
in the developing organ systems of the fetus.
如果在那关键阶段不接触重力
If you're not exposed to gravity during that critical phase...
发育基本上是很不正常的
the development is basically very abnormal.
1980年代的动物研究 结果令人担忧
An animal study conducted in the 1980s turned up troubling results...
影响到了胚胎的骨骼结构和心脏
affecting the embryo's skeletal structure and heart.
在生物实验卫星对老鼠胚胎的发育
There have been some studies done on the biocosmos satellites...
做过了一些研究
in which a developing rat embryo...
因为你是在失重的坏境中
because you're in a weightless environment...
所以在所有的胎儿骨骼的骨骼矿物质中
there's anywhere from a 13 to a 17-percent decrease...
都有13 17%的减少
in bone mineralization of all the fetal bones.
我们知道脊椎肌的肌肉群比较小
We know that the extensors along the spine are a smaller mass.
我们知道心脏的左心室实际上比较小的
We know that the left ventricle of the heart is actually smaller.
你要知道那是有道理的
And it makes sense when you consider that...
心室不必克服重力
that ventricle does not have to pump...
来泵送血液
against gravity to move blood.
尚不知同样的重力缺乏是否会影响到人类胎儿
It's unknown how the same lack of gravity might impact a human fetus...
但是极有可能会有类似的影响
but it's likely to have similar effects.
如果科学家能够找到办法
lf scientists can find a way...
让健康的人类婴儿在太空中长期生存
to bring a healthy human baby to term in space...
那么全新的产房将是必不可少的
then a whole new kind of delivery room will be required.
太空分娩将是太空中的脏活
Giving birth in space will be messy in space...
就像在地面上一样
just like it is here on the ground.
你会看到水 液体 血液
You have liquids and fluids involved, and blood.
你会碰到液体到处飞溅
You have the chance of liquids flying everywhere...
因此需要有通风系统和清洗系统
so ventilation systems and cleaning systems...
来帮助分娩过程
need to be developed to help the birth process.
太空建筑师约翰.斯宾塞也在思考
Space architect John Spencer has given some thought...
零重力产房的运作方式
to how a zero-gravity birthing chamber might work.
零重力产房的设计要求之一
One of the design requirements of a zero-gravity birthing chamber...
将会是较快的水流
will be a fairly rapid flow of water.
原因就在清洁
And the reason for that is cleanliness...
但是也要保持产房的血液干净
but also keeping the chamber clear of blood...
因此助产医生实际上
so that doctors who are helping with the birthing...
可以关注到方方面面
can actually see everything that is going on.
约翰的灵感来自水中分娩
John was inspired by water birthing...
婴儿在温水中分娩
in which babies are delivered into warm water.
这个方法的支持者认为它能从子宫舒适地
Proponents of the method say it eases the transition...
过渡到小生命脱离母体
from the womb to life outside the mother.
约翰还认为失重将提供类似的好处
John also believes weightlessness will provide similar benefits.
你在子宫里
When you're in the womb...
就像一开始就处在零重力下
it's like being in zero gravity to begin with...
因此走出零重力的子宫环境
so going from a zero-gravity womb environment...
来到零重力产房环境有可能更容易过渡
to a zero-gravity room environment might be an easier transition.
基于我们所知的一切 那一天依然遥遥无期
Based on all we know, that day is still very far in the future.
归根结底就是
Here's what it all boils down to.
如果重力影响到脊椎动物发展的方方面面
lf gravity affects all aspects of vertebrate development...
那么就会产生深远的影响
then there are profound implications...
前提是你考虑到了
when you consider successful procreation...
在地外环境中成功生育
in an extraterrestrial environment.
影响之一就是太空中出生的婴儿
One of those implications is that babies born in space...
有可能在访问地球时遇上困难
might have a difficult time visiting Earth.
我们几乎能遇上的人 今后百年里
We'll mostly likely meet people, a hundred years from now...
会是在那些环境中进化过来的
who have evolved in those environments.
如果他们来到地球
If they come to Earth...
就会需要穿上一套地球服
they're going to need to wear an Earth suit...
就像外骨骼之类的东西
which will have an exoskeleton kind of thing...
来帮助他们较弱的肌肉
which helps them with their weaker muscles...
较弱的骨骼等等
and weaker bones and everything.
所以这很有趣 我们最终要创造一个太空物种
So it's interesting. We're going to create eventually...
他们将需要一套地球服
a space species who will need an Earth suit...
回到自己的母亲地球
to return to the mother planet.
一个潜在的解决之道就是在太空中
One possible solution is to create artificial gravity...
利用离心机来产生重力
in space using centrifuges.
离心机利用离心力
Centrifuges use centrifugal force...
产生的效果叫做附加重力
to create an effect known as gravity loading.
你可以设想妇女 孕妇
You can imagine a woman, a pregnant woman...
坐在一头 甚至躺下
seated at one end or even laying down...
她的双脚对着机器的中心
with her feet towards the center of it.
她可以看书 工作 交流 什么都可以
She could be reading, working, talking to people, whatever...
可能要持续上一到两小时
and that might go on for an hour or two...
足以产生上下的感觉
enough so that there's a feeling of up and down...
有可能对胎儿是有益的
that might be beneficial for the fetus.
首个婴儿在外部世界降生
The first baby to be born off-world...
将会是惊人的体验
is going to be an amazing, amazing experience.
那将是人类历史性的一天
And it's going to be a historic day for humanity.
科学家认为那只是时间的问题
Scientists think it's only a matter of time.
我想我们最终将会在太空中繁育
I think eventually we will be reproducing in space.
我们只需要搞明白如何将它做好
We just need to figure out how to do it right.
搞明白如何将它做好的机会要好于
What better opportunity to figure out how to do it right...
航天局规划的三年火星任务
than NASA's planned three-year mission to Mars.
但是会邀请何种性别登上此次行程?
But will sex be invited along for the ride?
6500万年前
Sixty-five million years ago...
另一个物种主宰着人类今天主宰的行星
another species dominated the planet as humans do today.
恐龙曾经是地球上杰出的生命
The dinosaurs were the preeminent life forms on Earth...
超过了1.5亿年
for over 150 million years...
但是一切就在一个极其糟糕的下午
but all it took was one single very bad afternoon...
将它们永远抹去了
and that took them out of the picture forever...
一去不复返了
and they never came back.
人类离开地球的重要原因
The reason that it's important...
就在于假如我们不走
for human beings to get off the planet is that if we don't...
那么地球本身就是一个单点故障
the Earth itself is a single-point failure.
如果你没有备份
If you don't have a backup...
如果你没有替代之道
if you don't have an alternate pathway...
如果单项循环破裂
if that one critical link breaks...
那么整个系统将要经历灾难性的失败
then the whole system undergoes a catastrophic failure.
但要是繁衍没发生
But if reproduction doesn't happen...
要是繁衍不成功
and if it doesn't happen successfully...
物种将不复存在
the species is not going to survive.
尽管有这样的警告 但是人类的性行为和繁衍
Despite such warnings, human sexuality and reproduction...
依然是航天局的禁忌话题
remains a taboo subject at NASA.
航天局真是个令人难以置信的机构
NASA is really an incredible organization.
真是个令人惊诧不已的地方
It's an amazing place to be.
然而 航天局是个工程师们的组织
However, NASA is an organization...
依靠工程师 服务工程师
of engineers, by engineers, and for engineers.
对于工程师来说
To an engineer, the light switch is either on...
电灯不是开就是关
or the light switch is off.
没有灰色地带
There's no gray area.
在生命科学领域
In the life sciences...
只有两种绝对性 生与死
there are only two absolutes: life and death...
其它的一切就是灰色地带
and everything else is a shade of gray.
至于太空性事
As far as sex in space...
在我在航天局里呆过的那些年里
in all the years that I spent at NASA...
我不记得与宇航员或任务管理层
I don't recall ever having a conversation about it...
有过这方面的交流
with a crew or with mission management...
因此它还没有成为一个大问题
so it just hasn't been a big concern.
航天局的钱来自纳税人
NASA is funded by taxpayers...
纳税人想知道自己的钱并未用于
and taxpayers want to know that their dollars are not being used...
宇航员在外太空戏耍
for astronauts frolicking in outer space...
把钱花在太空出轨行动上
having space escapades at their expense.
老百姓想知道他们的税款
The public wants to know that their tax dollar...
使用得当
is being used wisely...
这就是航天局对整个想法如此胆怯的原因所在
and that's why NASA is so skittish about the whole concept.
很好 我们收到了 声音不错
Okay, we copy that. Sounds good.
目前航天局已经计划在2020年
NASA currently has plans to return humans to the Moon...
人类重返月球
by the year 2020.
那只是一场热身
That's just a warmup for the main event...
重头戏是为期三年的火星之旅
a three-year voyage to Mars and back.
在这个任务的总体规划中
In its master plan for the mission...
航天局只字未提人类性行为
NASA left out all references to human sexuality...
忽略引用美国国家科学院的一份报告
an omission cited in a report by the National Academy of Sciences.
至于太空性事
As far as sexuality in space...
那是个根本未曾研究过的领域
that's an area that hasn't been researched at all.
心理学家和精神病专家已经达成共识
Psychologists and psychiatrists have come to conclude...
人类需要沟通以保持正常的功能
that humans need to be connected in order for normal functioning.
我们需要心理沟通
We need to be psychologically connected...
我们需要情感沟通
we need to be emotionally connected...
我们同样需要人与人之间的身体沟通
and we also need to have some physical connectivity with individuals.
因此在这些不同层次上的亲昵是非常重要的
So intimacy at all these different levels is very important.
长期太空成员的问题
The problem with long-duration space crews...
是迄今为止 已经定型
is that the model, to date, has been one that precludes...
排除了任何一种亲昵行为
any sort of intimacy.
有些专家认为 宇航员为了任务
Some experts believe that astronauts...
应该被指望升华自己的
should be expected to sublimate their needs and desires...
需求和欲望
for the sake of the mission.
那是不切实际的 是不可能做到的
That's unrealistic, and it's not going to happen.
那会导致人功能失常
It would lead to very dysfunctional individuals...
只要他们能坚持这种独立生活的话
if they were able to maintain that kind of separateness.
因此为了让团队发挥作用
So, in order for the team to be functional...
所有各种层次的亲昵 将不仅是人的正常功能
intimacy on all these different levels is going to be part and parcel...
而且还是计划所需要的重要部分
of just normal human functioning, and we need to plan for that.
反对意见是机组成员的性别
The counterargument is that sex between crew members...
可能会产生危害 分散精力与隔阂
could create dangerous distractions and divisions.
争论可能会出现 问题可能会产生
Arguments may occur, problems may happen...
争吵可能会发生
tiffs may happen.
一个人有可能会嫉妒其他人
One person might get jealous over another person...
或者有可能开始垂涎另一个情侣 等等
or might start lusting for another partner, something like that.
会有这样的情况的
That will happen.
这是难以避免的
It's going to be hard to avoid it.
我们是人
We are human beings...
可能会有小问题出现的
and there could be petty issues that may pop up...
不过你会有很长的时间来倾诉 来沟通
but you have a long time to talk it out, communicate it.
派遣单一性别成员已经被建议为
Sending single-gender crews has been suggested...
是防止长期任务中的性行为的一个措施
as a way to inhibit or prevent sex on long-duration missions.
我认为这是个不切实际的想法
I think it's unrealistic to think...
就因为你派遣了一种性别
that just because you have all one gender...
就不会有性接触的需求
that there is not going to be any needs for sexual contact...
或就不会有性行为的发生
or that sex won't happen.
我认为这是一种幼稚的做法
l think that's kind of a naive approach.
另一项计划要求只派遣夫妇
Another plan calls for sending only married couples.
这也是不切实际的想法
It's also unrealistic to expect that simply being married...
把结婚来作为解决方案
is going to be the solution.
所以我不认为婚姻是万无一失的解决之道
So I don't think that marriage is a foolproof way to approach it...
并不比派遣单一性别好到哪里
any more than to send all one gender.
我认为我们需要的是人选
I think that what we need to do is to select individuals...
感情上成熟
who are emotionally mature...
性生活满足
who are comfortable in their sexuality...
然后你对他们训练 处理所遇到的问题
and then you give them training to deal with issues as they come up...
接下来你只需相信他们能够做好就完了
and then you simply have to trust them to do a good job.
雪儿的想法是让宇航员们
Sheryl's idea is to have the crew...
首先在一个地方一起生活九个月
first live together for nine months in a location...
那地方要反映出火星与世隔绝的环境
that mirrors the isolated environment of Mars.
她想到了南极
She suggests Antarctica.
我们进行测试的一个方法
One of the ways we can test this out...
就是将他们送到南极度过九个月的冬季
is to send them down to Antarctica to winter over for nine months.
在此期间
During that period of time...
他们不仅可以了解到他们有哪些社会问题
they can not only work out how their social issues are...
而且他们还可以了解到有哪些个人关系问题
but they can work out any intimacy issues.
他们可以了解到 如果他们相互吸引
They can find out if they're going to be attracted to each other...
如果是这样 他们将如何来处置
and, if they are, how are they going to deal with that...
团队将如何来处置
and how the group is going to deal with that.
这样 一旦我们真的将他们
That way, when we actually put them...
用太空火箭送到火星去
in the space rocket to send them off to Mars...
或将他们送到月球定居
or to send them to the Moon to inhabit there...
他们就会知道预计到什么 知道如何去处置
they'll know what to expect, and they'll know how to deal with it.
我认为要抱这样的态度 即他们是内行
I think that taking the attitude that they're professionals...
他们只是在困惑于处理的方法
and they'll just muddle their way through...
这才是应对灾难的方法
is a recipe for disaster.
尽管航天局
Despite NASA's denials...
否认他们回避这个问题的历史
and their history of avoiding the subject...
但是有人称性行为已经在美国宇航飞行中发生过
some say sex has already occurred on a U.S. space flight.
有人相信凭空瞎想
Some believe it's unrealistic to think...
在数百名敢做敢为的冒险家里头
that out of the hundreds of adventurous risk-takers...
他们已经进入过太空
who've rocketed into space...
至少有两位不是从事某些宇宙对接的
that at least two of them didn't engage in some cosmic coupling.
我不会感到惊讶 如果说性行为已经在太空发生过
I wouldn't be surprised if sex has already happened in space.
我的意思是 我们在航天局的航天飞机上有过夫妻档
I mean, we've had a married couple on the NASA shuttle.
如果你在地球上做过 为何不在太空中一试呢?
And if you've done it on Earth, wouldn't you try it in space?
所说的夫妇就是宇航员简.戴维斯和马克.李
The married couple in question are astronauts Jan Davis and Mark Lee.
1992年 戴维斯和李升空
In 1992, Davis and Lee blasted off...
参加了奋进号航天飞机为期7天的任务
for a seven-day mission aboard the space shuttle Endeavour.
航天局没有太空中禁止性行为的官方政策
NASA has no official policy banning sex in space.
航天局没有告诉人们 你不能性交
NASA has not told people you must not have sexual intercourse.
预计人们会说
People are expected...
鬼才相信呢
"to know better than that."
但是他们确实有个政策 针对已婚夫妇进入太空
But they do have a policy against sending married couples into space.
戴维斯和李在任务训练期间相识
Davis and Lee met during mission training...
一见钟情 结婚赶在了升空前
fell in love, and wed just before liftoff.
因为这给替换其中的一人参加任务造成太大的混乱
Because it would have been too disruptive...
航天局做出了一个例外
to replace one of them on the mission, NASA made an exception.
机组其他成员会允许他们的私生活吗?
Could the rest of the crew have allowed them some private time?
有可能机组成员共谋
It is possible that the crew members did collude...
帮助这对已婚夫妇在上面做些勾当
to help the married couple do something up there...
但是高度怀疑
but it's highly doubtful just considering...
考虑到宇航员的保守性
the conservative nature of the astronauts...
航天局的保守性会允许这样的事情发生
the conservative nature of NASA to allow for such a thing to take place.
我不会说 我希望他们破坏规矩
I wouldn't say that I would hope that they broke regulations...
但是我会说 我希望他们利用这个机会
but I could say that I hope that they utilized...
来一次花烛洞房
the opportunity to consummate a union...
在这个条件 环境 任务中
in an environment and a situation and a mission...
真正欢庆一下两个人类的美满婚姻
that truly celebrated the beauty of the union of two human beings.
如果这对夫妇确实干过了
If the couple did engage...
他们的隐私选择其实是有限的
their options for privacy were limited.
航天飞机的乘务区
The crew area of the space shuttle...
总共才2200立方英尺
comprises just over 2,200 cubic feet...
其大小相当于一个中等面积的起居室
about the same area as an average-sized living room.
对于航天飞机来说
In terms of the space shuttle orbiter...
玩XX的最佳地方
the best place to have sex...
就是通往货舱的气闸室
is the airlock leading out into the cargo bay.
这里足以容纳两个人
It's big enough for two people.
要说航天飞机上有什么地方的话 这里就是可能之地
If there's any place onboard the shuttle, that's where it might happen.
如今的国际空间站远比航天飞机来的宽敞
Today's International Space Station is far roomier than the space shuttle...
15个舱位有1.26万立方英尺
with 12,600 cubic feet spread over 15 modules.
我非常熟悉国际空间站
I'm very familiar with the interiors...
目前的内部情况
of the current International Space Station...
空间站较为私密的地方
and the more intimate areas of that space station...
实际上就是俄罗斯舱
are actually the Russian modules.
他们比较个性化 举个例子
They're more personalized, for example...
那里就是会发生的地方
and that's where it would basically happen...
俄罗斯舱
in the Russian modules.
马克.李和简.戴维斯
Mark Davis and Jan Lee...
一直拒绝证实或否认谣言
have refused to confirm or deny the rumors...
留下的只有猜测
leaving only speculation...
关于是否有人涉足了最后的边界
as to whether anyone has probed the final frontier.
事实上 每天分分秒秒
The fact that every single minute of the day...
都被地球上的
is logged and looked at...
控制中心记录关注着
by Mission Control here on the planet Earth...
你会意识到 或许最不切合实际
you realize that it's perhaps the most impractical...
最无情趣 最无性感的浪漫之地就是外太空
and unromantic and unsexy place for romance in outer space.
你一旦成为了宇航员 你就不会想做任何事情
Once you become an astronaut, you don't want to do anything...
有可能会危及你另一次太空飞行机会的事情了
that might jeopardize your opportunity to have another flight in space.
要我打赌 我会赌俄罗斯人
If I had a bet, I would bet that the Russians...
已经较多地涉及了零重力性事
have been more involved in the issue of zero-gravity sex...
太空中玩性超过了美国人
and sex in space than the Americans have.
俄罗斯人要更加开放一些
The Russians are a little bit more open-minded.
他们在太空中玩吉它
They have guitars in space.
他们过去甚至在空间站里
They've even in the past had cigarettes...
抽烟 喝酒
onboard space stations, and liquor.
为什么不呢?
And why not?
猜测是否发生过太空性行为
Speculating about whether sex in space has happened...
或是否有宇航员干过
or whether astronauts have done it...
把它归类于小报心态吧
relegates it to the category of tabloid mentality.
我认为问题不在于
I think that the question is not...
它是否实际发生过
whether it actually has happened or not...
而在于我们需要度过关于是否有过太空性行为
but we need to get past that whole titillation...
整个挠痒痒的过程
about whether there's been sex in space...
也就是说太空中会有性事的
and say there will be sex in space...
我们必须中断整个问题所带来的烦恼
and we need to stop agonizing over the whole issue.
无论是否发生过没有
Regardless of whether it has happened...
大家都同意太空性事
everyone agrees that sex in space...
带有一定的优势和劣势
comes with certain advantages and disadvantages.
我认为人在太空中模样会更好看一些
I think people are better-looking in space.
脸会变得更加红润 女人的胸脯会更大一些
The faces get a little bit more flush, women's breasts get larger.
由于脸庞有一点点浮肿 皱纹就会消失
With the face being a little more puffy, the wrinkles go away.
腿会更细 因为血液较少流向那里
The legs are thinner because there's less fluid down there.
女性无需胸罩 因为没有什么把它往下拉
Women don't need bras because there's nothing to pull them down.
但是看着更加性感 无助你全力应对
But looking sexier doesn't help you grapple...
微重力性事的物理学
with the physics of micro-gravity sex.
正如我们在重力一号上所见 来自你情侣的细微轻推
As we saw on G-Force One, the slightest nudge from your partner...
都会让你打转转
can send you reeling.
问题是你还是获得了力道
The problem is you've still got mass.
如果有人推别人非常用力
If somebody was to push down on somebody very hard...
就会将他们送往另一个方向
it could send them off in another direction...
越过飞船的舱位 会造成严重的伤害
across the cabin of a spaceship and could do severe damage.
你会将阴鸡鸡整个折断
You can break a penis physically.
其实是非常困难的 要知道
And it's actually very difficult to then, you know...
再次结合在一起是很难的
do the operation to get it all back together again.
面对挑战 专家会不会说
In light of the challenges, what would the experts say...
如果他们受邀进入太空
if they were invited into space...
将会一击中G点呢? (注: 双关语)
to have a go at hitting the zero-g spot?
当然啦
Sure.
噢 没错 我到了那里 到了那里
Oh, yeah. I'd be there, I'd be there.
迫不及待就想来个太空XX
I would have sex in space instantly.
我是个科学家 作为科学家 我们会当旁观者
I'm a scientist, and as a scientist, we like to observe...
我们会远距离研究 但是我们不会参与
we like to study from a distance, but we don't like to partake.
我们不会干涉我们所研究的课题
We don't like to interfere with the subject we are studying.
对 我老婆说我只能和她在太空中玩XX
Yeah, my wife said l could only have sex in space with her.
我真的不知道
I really don't know.
这种事情 我真的没有想过
It's something I've really not thought about.
我想到的更多的是在太空中生孩子
I've thought more about giving birth in space actually.
我们看到了万那的创意
We've seen Vanna Bonta's concept...
如何在微重力环境中性亲昵
for how to accomplish sexual intimacy in micro-gravity.
另一个办法 据说曾经试验过
Another method, supposedly once tested...
在航天局的水槽里用来训练宇航员
in the tanks NASA uses to train astronauts...
叫做三海豚技术
is called the three-dolphin technique.
有时两条海豚很难进行交配
Two dolphins sometimes have a hard time coupling together.
第三者可以迫使它们呆在一起
A third one that can press them together actually makes it easier...
实际上可以更容易地使它们进行交配
for the coupling process to happen.
这也很可能发生在零重力环境中
That may well happen in zero gravity also.
你可能想有个第三者
You might want to have a third person...
来敦促你 或你坚持在
that helps facilitate you or keeps you in the middle...
零重力环境中
of the zero-gravity environment.
唯一的问题就是无人操心去告诉海豚
The only problem is no one bothered to tell dolphins...
所谓的三海豚技术
about the three-dolphin technique.
海洋生物学家称这纯属瞎掰
Marine biologists say it's not true.
大家形成共识的一件事是
One thing everyone does agree upon...
一个或多个性伙伴必须限制
is that one or more of the mating partners needs to be restrained.
你能看到的是一些扶手
What you could have is some handholds...
或者类似于夹脚
and perhaps legholds similar--
某种材料做成的杆子
made out of bar kind of material--
类似于你帮助你进入浴缸的扶手
similar to the handholds you have to assist you in a bathtub.
约束活动的模拟装置
Any mechanism that would simulate constraints on motion...
完全是模拟重力 或许可以帮助太空交媾
that would at all mimic gravity could probably facilitate mating in space.
它可以是尼龙扣
It could be Velcro.
当事人一方可以在腿上缠上一些东西
And one of the parties could wrap legs around something...
能够固定他或她的膝盖
and be able to secure him or herself with their knees.
我认为人类的聪明才智会给出答案的
I think that human ingenuity will give us answers...
我们对此不能胡思乱猜
that we can't hypothetically guess at.
一旦你将人放入那个环境
That when you actually put people in the environment...
他们是会找出办法来的
they'll figure a way to do it.
或许固定脚就是类似于那种东西
And then perhaps footholds similar to the kind of things...
把你的双脚固定在滑水板来保证立足
you put your feet in in water skis to secure the bottom.
对于太空性事 我认为你可能需要带上安全带
For sex in space, I think you might want a seatbelt.
我们已经在太空心肺复苏方面做了大量的工作
We have done a lot of work trying to do CPR in space.
你只要想想 心肺复苏不是就类似于
And when you think about it, cardiopulmonary resuscitation...
两个人之间的
is a similar kind of complex act, you know...
复杂的活动吗?
between two people, right?
我们已经形成了这个大系统 用来做心肺复苏
We evolved this big system where you would do CPR.
我们对于这个系统投入了大量的考量
We put a lot of thought into that system.
你知道宇航员在评价该系统时
You know what the astronauts decided early on...
原先的判断吗?
when they evaluated the system?
他们断定该系统太繁琐了
They decided the system was too cumbersome...
他们完全可以用胶带来完成的
and they could do it all with duct tape.
我不是说胶带是太空性事的辅助手段
I'm not saying that duct tape is a sexual aid in space.
我只是说胶带就像是原力
I'm just saying duct tape is like The Force.
它具有两面性 可以将宇宙绑定在一起
It has a light side and dark side, and it binds the universe together.
哈维的发明在我听来非常不错
Harvey's invention sounds very good to me.
一方面 它不涉及第三者插足
For one thing, it doesn't involve a third party...
即所谓的海豚效应
the so-called dolphin effect...
那个在我看来非常不舒服
which l think would be quite uncomfortable for me.
关于微重力中的交媾
Speculating about coupling in micro-gravity...
可能很快就会成为过去的事情
may soon be a thing of the past.
为未来的全新性视野做好准备
Get ready for a sexy new vision of the future...
是私人航天业界的待客之道
courtesy of the private space industry.
不久前曾经有过一段时间
There was a time not so long ago...
太空旅游和太空游客是性感的缩影
when space travel and space travelers were the epitome of sexiness.
太空在1960年代非常性感
Space was very sexy in the 1960s.
如果你问任何一位宇航员
If you ask any of the astronauts...
他们是1960年代太空计划的一部分
who were part of the space program in the 1960s...
他们会告诉你 他们实际上就像是性神
they will all tell you that they were actually sort of sex gods.
两件事给太空旅游兜头浇了冷水
Two things became the equivalent of a cold shower for space travel.
一是对于普通老百姓
One, the promise of average citizens...
进入太空的承诺从未兑现
traveling into space was never fulfilled.
休斯顿现在牢牢控制
Houston now controlling.
人们得到的印象
People got the impression that the shuttle...
是航天飞机也会商业化的
was something that would also be commercialized.
因此他们在70年代激动不已
So they got all excited about it in the seventies...
探月计划引出了这个有点性感的
coming out of this sort of sexy era of space...
太空地带
with the Moon program...
后来普通老百姓大大失望了
and then the general public were vastly disappointed.
主发动机点火 升空
We have main engine start and liftoff.
第二件事是挑战者号爆炸
The second thing was the Challenger explosion.
我认为那件事带来了真正的转变
I think that caused a real change...
老百姓态度的巨变
sea change in the public's attitude.
他们开始转变要去太空的想法
They began to discount the idea that they would ever go to space.
但是所有这些即将改变 幸亏私人航天产业
But that's all about to change, thanks to the private space industry.
首个太空旅游公司所采用的飞机是维珍银河号
The first space tourism venture to take flight is Virgin Galactic...
是英国亿万富翁理查德.布兰森爵士的创意
brainchild of British billionaire Sir Richard Branson.
理查德.布兰森的维珍银河正在销售自己的机票
Richard Branson's Virgin Galactic is selling their tickets...
每人花20万美元到太空边缘
for $200,000 apiece to go up to the edge of space...
约62英里处
which is about 62 miles.
那是我们可以真正体验太空经历最接近的地方
And it is the closest we can get to a true space experience.
维珍银河号的处女航还要再等上几年
Virgin Galactic's maiden voyage is still a few years away.
然而这并没有妨碍性冒险
But that hasn't stopped the sexually adventurous...
通过咨询私人航班来烧钱
with money to burn from inquiring about private flights.
他们咨询了有关太空度蜜月的想法
They've inquired about the idea of having their honeymoon in space...
实际上是
and, actually, as part of that process...
作为太空完婚的一部分
consummating their marriage in space.
那个想法
And that is an idea...
我们是不会贸然跟进的
that we are not going to follow up with to start with.
我们需要更多地了解他们可能会遇到的风险
We need to understand much better the risks...
然后我们才会
that they could encounter before we would even contemplate the idea...
考虑人们的想法
of allowing somebody who's a honeymooner...
那些想在太空完婚的度蜜月者的想法
to consummate their marriage in space.
然而事实上关键在于
But the fact of the matter is...
有些人确实想尝试一下
is that some people do want to do this.
开拓性的维珍银河
Groundbreaking as Virgin Galactic is...
相对太空旅游协会的大手笔
it's small potatoes compared to what...
只能算是小菜一碟
the Space Tourism Society is cooking up.
你听说过一英里高空俱乐部吧
You've heard of the mile-high club.
我一直在讨论200英里高空俱乐部
I've been talking about the 200-mile-high club.
我们认为超级游艇或邮轮围绕着地球
We see super yachts or cruise ships in orbit around the Earth...
或巡游在地球与月球之间
or circling between the Earth and the Moon...
那才是真正的太空旅游的关键元素
as a key element to true space tourism.
我们谈到了娱乐
We're talking about entertainment.
我们谈到了玩耍
We're talking about fun.
我们谈到了吃喝 我们谈到了性
We're talking about drinking. We're talking about sex.
我们谈到了所有疯狂的东西
We're talking about all sorts of wild and crazy things here.
展望2050年
Leaping ahead to the year 2050...
来看看新婚夫妇的蜜月体验
let's see what a newlywed couple might experience...
乘坐约翰.斯潘塞
on their honeymoon aboard a space yacht...
设计的太空游艇
designed by John Spencer.
这就是约翰的太空游艇样机
This is a mockup of John's space yacht.
我设计了一个迪斯科舞厅
I'm designing a discotheque.
就是中间的那部分
This would be right here in the center section here.
是一个中心球
This would be a central sphere.
试想 如果你愿意 一个直径60英尺的大球
Imagine, if you will, a giant 60-foot-diameter sphere...
几乎完全是玻璃或类似玻璃材料制作的
that will be almost completely glass or some type of glass-like material...
你可以看到全景
and you can see in all directions.
你可以看到人们到处漂动 跳舞
And then you'll have people floating around and dancing...
游荡 做着各种各样的事情
and sailing and doing all sorts of things...
娱乐 消遣 找乐子
for entertainment and for pleasure and for fun.
现在 经过了漫漫长夜的歌舞狂欢
Now, after a long night of dancing and carousing...
大尽兴后
and having a lot of fun...
小夫妻想来一点更好玩的
the couple want to have a little bit more fun.
在地球上 那有可能是在浴盆里的浪漫插曲
On Earth, that might include a romantic interlude in a hot tub.
约翰.斯潘塞预想了一个太空浴盆
John Spencer envisions a space-based hot tub...
他称之为浴球
he calls a "hot sphere."
你想象得出你的蜜月套房是个球形
You can imagine that your honeymoon suite is a sphere...
其中央是彩色温水
and within the center of that is this colored warm water.
你可以浸泡在其中
And in that, you can immerse yourselves...
相互搂抱 做爱 宽慰
hanging on to each other for lovemaking or relaxing.
球将停留在大量的气流里
The sphere will be kept in place within the volume by airflow.
因此它不会移动 而你可以溅起水
So it won't move around, but you can splash...
水会变成小珠状回到球里面
and the water will come right back as little spheres into it.
经过了在浴球里的浸泡
After a soak in the hot sphere...
我们这对小夫妇回蜜月套房就寝
our couple retires to their honeymoon suite.
在那里 他们会看到山姆对抗牛顿第三定律的杰作
There they'll find Sam's rebuttal to Newton's third law--
依偎管道
the snuggle tunnel.
假装这是蜜月套房里的大窗户
So pretend this is a giant window inside the honeymoon suite.
我们会看到美妙的全景
So we have the fantastic panoramic view...
然后他们可以将这东西展开
and then they can expand this thing here...
这就是所谓的依偎管道
which is known as the snuggle tunnel.
里面有照明 通风
We'll have illumination inside, we'll have ventilation inside.
你可以看到里面毛茸茸的 必须是毛茸茸的
As you can see it's furry. Gotta have it furry.
必须柔软舒适 人们才可以在里头干事
Gotta make it soft and comfortable for people to do their thing.
他们进去了
They go in here.
然后他们依偎在依偎管道里
And then they're snuggling in the snuggle tunnel.
依偎隧道有可能成为
Might the snuggle tunnel become basic equipment...
维珍银河飞船2的基本设备吗?
on Virgin Galactic Spaceship 2?
这显然不是我们早期亚轨道
It's clearly not something for our early days...
太空旅游的用品
of suborbital space tourism.
但是 要知道 我一直效力于一个机构
But, you know, I'm very used to working in an organization...
在那里我们还考虑到了未来的情况
whereby we also think about the future.
事实上 有朝一日
And the fact is, one day there might be...
会出现飞船3 飞船4
a Spaceship 3 or a Spaceship 4.
依偎管道的概念是合乎逻辑的
And the concept of a snuggle tunnel of some sort is entirely logical.
航天局声势浩大推进依偎管道
Is it only a matter of time before NASA jumps...
是否只是个时间问题呢?
on the snuggle tunnel bandwagon?
我从来没听说过航天局
I've never heard of any plans at NASA...
有开发依偎管道的任何计划
to develop a snuggle tunnel.
因此也许不是这样
So maybe not.
尽管太空旅游产业鼓噪
But while the space tourism industry plays up...
更具挑逗的太空性事
the more titillating aspects of sex in space...
但是生命科学研究人员有着自己充满希望的思考
life sciences researchers have their own reasons for being hopeful.
我认为太空旅游就是太空玩性的场所
I think space tourism is the venue in which sex in space...
将被认为更加舒适 更加开放
will be addressed more comfortably and more openly...
我认为就会是那种环境
and I think that that will be the milieu...
那里最终会被舒适地对待
in which it will finally be comfortably dealt with.
似乎免不了 人们所到之处
It seems inevitable that where humans go...
性紧随而至
sex will surely follow...
即使是进了寒冷 广袤的宇宙间
even into the cold, vast reaches of the universe.
探索的全部就是你不仅是探索地点
The whole part of exploring is you're not only exploring locations...
而且还是探索我们 我们自己的前途
it's an exploration of ourselves, a perspective of ourselves.
其中有亲昵 做爱 关系
And part of that is intimacy, lovemaking, relationships.
我们的后裔不光是地球的
We are progeny of not just the Earth...
而且还是宇宙的
but of the cosmos.
对于后代 我们有责任
And as its progeny, it is our duty...
尽我们最大的能力将其延续到其它行星
to use the best of our ability and continue that into other planets.
谁知道我们会发现什么
Who knows what we'll find?
引用伟大诗人但丁的诗句: 天堂盘旋在我们头顶
To paraphrase the poet Dante, "The heavens swirl above us...
我们的眼睛还是盯着地面
"and our eyes are still cast to the ground."
性是人类生活的组成部分
Sex is part of the human experience...
人类走到哪 性也跟到哪
and wherever humans go, sex will go, too.
这就是逻辑 这就是理性
That's logical. It's rational.
这才是天经地义
That's the way it should be.